My lights are plug-in
我这摄影灯是接电的
They're the kind of high stand lights
属于那种高架的灯啊
Actually, I used to use TIM from Film Storm
其实我一直以前使用的是影视飓风TIM的
Their lights
他们的灯啊
Their lights are a bit more expensive
他们灯卖的比较贵
Later, they switched to the Godox brand lights
后来又用的神牛牌的灯
The stand for his TIM lights
他的那个TIM的灯的架子
Paired with the Godox light bulbs
加上神牛牌的这个灯的这个灯珠子
So it's quite convenient to match them together
所以来讲搭配的比较方便
The TIM lights can change to various colors
TIM的灯呢可以就是换各种色彩啊
And the stand is very suitable
而且他那个架子非常合适
It's actually his lights
其实是他的灯啊
This set of VLOG videos made me.
成就了我的这套VLOG视频啊
Actually, at the beginning, I shot them lying on a mattress.
也就是说其实我最开始是靠着床垫拍的
How did those episodes turn out?
那几期效果呢
Actually, they were pretty average because I was using natural light back then.
其实一般因为那时候都是用的自然光
Ever since I joined Bilibili, though,
后来自从来了B站以后
I got used to shooting my face with two lights.
就习惯了用两盏灯啊拍我自己的脸
Moving on,
然后来讲的话
using this lighting setup,
用这种灯光条件
plus cutting off all the indoor lights.
再加上室内的光全切
Let's cut off all the indoor light sources used for daily life.
就把室内的这个生活用的光源全部切断啊
Two powerful lights shine directly on my face. This creates the setting for my show. Actually, speaking of it, the one who should be credited for starting this is TIM. Even though I'm just a little Calamity just an old man, chuckle,
两盏强光就这么着打到我的脸上 这样创造了我这个节目 其实来讲的话 始作俑者还是他得感谢TIM啊 这在上面虽然我是个小卡拉咪 呵呵老头一个
I truly appreciate the ecosystem of Bilibili,
但是确实感谢B站这种生态
which sometimes can help many UPloaders.
有的时候能够帮助很多up主
Achieving your life dreams
实现自己的人生梦想
You see, now I notice that even a little bit of light
你看现在我就发现其实我稍微有一点光源的话
makes a big difference
效果就会好很多啊
even if it’s just a bit on the face
哪怕就是说在脸上补一点儿啊
Look, the effect is much better this way
你看这样效果就好很多了
In this approach
其实这种方式来讲
We often find in our daily lives
我们说呢很多的时候在你的生活当中呢
that you might unexpectedly
你会发现你不经意之间
find many skills coming together
很多的技能就会串在一起
Many things that truly catch your attention
很多事情真正啊能够给你注意的事情呢
are often the ones you initially didn't understand
可能是你最开始并不了解的
or were unaware of
并不知道的一些事情
but many times, things are just like that
但是很多的时候一些事情就是这样啊
happening when you least expect them
就是在你不经意之间
without you realizing it
不知道之间
creating all sorts of novel conditions for you
就会给你创造出各种各样的新奇的条件
If I switch to that camera mode now
你看现在如果我是打开那种摄像模式的话
the lighting will be more stable
它那个光就会比较稳定
Actually, a little bit of light is enough.
其实有一点点光就够了啊
We mainly listen to the sound in my videos.
我们说这个我的视频嘛主要是听个声啊
But now there's a bit of an echo. So there's nothing we can do about it. Because this place is particularly empty right now. As everyone knows, in general, my home in Beijing is piled high with stuff. So there's no echo there. But speaking of this new place,
但是现在呢又有点回音 所以没办法 因为现在这个甲特别的空 大家知道所有的东西来讲 我在那个北京的家家里都堆满了东西 所以他就没有什么回音 我在这个新家来讲的话
There will be a significant echo.
他就会有很大的回音啊
Because the room isn't very large.
因为没有家非常的大
It's quite empty.
非常的空
So it can't really be big and hollow, can it?
所以没有办法假大空吗
But I have to record inside the room.
可是我要在房间里边录呢
The sound will be much quieter then.
那声音就会更小啊
In any case,
无论如何
We've come this far.
我们现在已经到了这一步了啊
I was even talking about it with my partner.
我跟我搭档还说呢
I said we'd start shooting this Friday.
我说这周五就开始拍
Then he expressed his concerns.
然后他就说比较担心啊
What if the audience criticizes us?
出来以后观众骂怎么办
Because in the past, when he released his work,
因为他之前出来拍东西
he often faced criticism from the audience.
老老有观众骂之类的
I told him not to worry.
我说别担心
I won't let those malicious comments
我不会让那些恶意评论
get to you.
让你看见的
I'll make sure to delete them all.
我都会删干净的
It's okay.
没关系啊
When anyone does something,
任何人啊做一些事情来讲的话
there will be some resistance.
都会有一定的阻力
It's very normal.
这是很正常的事
For the topic of this episode,
按我们这一期的主题来讲
I'm holding my phone now,
哎我现在拿着手机
I can check the theme of this episode.
我就可以看一下我们这一期主题
I want to see what my inspiration was all about.
我想看我的灵感主要写了什么啊
It's about why many cities ban motorcycles.
啊就是这个很多城市为什么要禁摩啊
Banning motorcycles is actually a significant logic.
禁摩其实是一个很大的一个逻辑
I want to tell everyone,
我要跟大家说
encouraging people to learn how to ride motorcycles, to ride motorcycles, why do some cities ban motorcycles? it's because banning motorcycles can affect housing prices, not banning them would also impact housing prices,
让大家去学摩托车啊 去这个开摩托车啊 为什么一些城市要禁摩呢 是因为禁摩这种东西呢会影响房价啊 不禁摩就会影响房价
first, look at learning to ride,
首先你看啊学车啊
it usually costs between 4,000 to 6,000.
车一般都要4000~6000啊
Learning to ride a motorcycle costs around one thousand three hundred to one thousand six hundred.
学摩托车呢一千三一千六就学了
To put it simply, if you buy a motorcycle,
摩托车呢说白了买一个摩托车啊
it can cost from five thousand to tens of thousands of yuan,
五六千块钱到几万块钱
even over a hundred thousand yuan.
几10万都有
But generally, it’s around a thousand yuan.
但是一般来讲都是千把块钱
But if you buy a car,
但是你买一个汽车呢
even a car costing tens of thousands could be in bad shape,
可能买个几万的汽车都是很破
most cars cost over a hundred thousand yuan,
一般都十几万
or two hundred thousand yuan.
20万
over 300,000
30多万
right?
对不对
a bit much
多了点
and then there are cars that cost over a million
然后甚至有上百万的车
riding a motorcycle has one advantage
骑摩托车呢有一个好处呢
you can weave through traffic, right?
就是可以四处钻对吧
you're not affected by traffic jams
可以不受这个堵车的影响
so it's really more convenient
所以他就是真的是比较方便
there's no such thing as parking for motorcycles
骑摩托车也没有什么所谓的停车
So you see, from buying a car, learning to drive, to parking, it all costs money.
所以你看从买车学车到这个停车位啊
Parking fees and all that add up.
停车费这些东西都是钱
But motorcycles are a tool for the masses.
但是摩托车呢它就是一个平民化的工具
They allow ordinary people to enjoy themselves.
它就能让普通老百姓呢能够很乐呵
That's why many cities either ban motorcycles in the downtown area,
所以很多城市呢要不就在主城区禁摩
or prohibit them throughout the entire city.
要不就是全域禁摩啊
However, in daily life, it's impossible to completely eliminate such vehicles. So they came up with these awkward electric scooters. Charging an electric bike is also relatively slow. Right? And its range is limited.
但是呢生活当中呢 又没有办法完完全全的取消这种东西 但他们所以就弄出来一个不伦不类的电瓶车啊 电瓶车呢充电呢又比较缓慢 是不是 而他续航有限
But with a motorcycle, you have a motorcycle,
但是摩托车呢你有了摩托车
you could even ride from Beijing all the way to Tibet.
你甚至可以从北京一直骑到西藏啊
Ride all the way to Xinjiang without any issues.
一直骑到新疆都没有问题
You can complete a motorcycle trip.
可以完成摩旅
So, what’s the thing about this,
所以这个东西呢
what kind of risk does it pose?
它是有一个什么样的危害在里边呢
It's like iron wrapped in meat.
就是说是肉包铁
But actually, this thing
但其实这个东西呢
Every time the danger of motorcycles is promoted,
每次宣传摩托车的危险性时候
various media will emphasize it heavily,
各种媒体都会大树特树
how dangerous motorcycles are,
这摩托车危险啊
look, all the motorcycle influencers have died.
你看机车网红全死了呀
What can you do?
你看怎么着
But if you just drive slowly,
但是其实你开慢点
riding a high-end scooter is fine.
开个大牌踏板是没有问题的啊
Why do I keep pointing out the various downsides of motorcycles?
为什么又说这摩托车各种各样的不好的地方呢
Because if you think about it, if you live in the suburbs,
因为你想如果你在郊区生活
and you work in the city,
然后你在城里上班
riding a motorcycle is actually the fastest way to commute.
你骑摩托车其实是最快的通勤方法
It's even faster than the subway.
它甚至比地铁快
Driving a car will get you stuck in traffic,
你开车会堵车
and finding parking during the morning rush hour can be a real issue.
开车早上早高峰上下班停车都是问题
So I've always recommended that people use motorcycles,
所以我一直推荐大家呢用摩托车
especially in cities where they aren't banned.
特别是在没禁摩的城市
Or you could ride a motorcycle in from the suburbs
或者在郊区能开摩托车进来
Ride a motorcycle
开摩托
If there’s no way to avoid riding a motorcycle, we can’t really prohibit it Then you should try to use an electric scooter instead So riding an electric scooter is also convenient for parking And it’s not expensive, costing just a few thousand bucks Well So, in terms of status, it might be
摩托车实在没有办法给你禁摩现磨 那么你就尽量开个电瓶车 所以骑电瓶车也是停车也方便啊 价格几千块钱也不贵 然后呢 所以说就是身份上可能啊
You might have a girlfriend
可能你交女朋友
Or carrying a family of three isn't exactly easy.
或者那个驮着一家三口不太容易
But actually, the cost of owning a car,
但其实你用车成本啊
car loans and mortgages are similar,
车贷和房贷也是一样的
it helps to bridge the gap between urban and rural areas.
它本身来讲缩进了城乡之间的距离
So why are they willing to let you use it in rural areas,
所以为什么农村之间他愿意用让你用呢
but not in cities?
城市之间他都不愿意让你用呢
Because it shortens the distance between them,
就是因为你这样来讲缩短中情距离
which leads to more people developing the subway systems,
那给你那么多人去开发的这个地铁啊
and more people maintaining the automotive industry.
那么多人去维护的这个这个汽车工业啊
Are you the person who collects parking fees at the parking lot?
停车是不是停车场停车的收费人员
What else could they be doing?
那人家干什么去啊
Right?
对不对
So that's how it is.
所以来讲就是这样
Why is the United States seen as a country on wheels?
美国为什么是汽车的这个轮子上的country of view啊
Why is it considered a country on wheels?
这个为什么是轮子上的国家
It's because of its cities.
就是因为他的那个城市
Its transportation system.
它这个transportation
Its public transportation isn't particularly good.
它的公共的这个交通呢不是特别的好啊
Public transportation isn't particularly good
公共交通不是特别好
between cities
城与城
and between states
州与州之间呢
towns are also quite far apart
镇与镇之间的又比较远
so without a car it's absolutely not feasible in America even riding a motorcycle isn't convenient because there are many places where the weather might not be great which could make motorcycle riding quite exhausting But when it comes to riding cars,
所以他没有车来讲的话 在美国是万万不行的 甚至你在美国骑摩托车也是不方便的 因为有很多地方他有一些天气可能不太好啊 可能骑摩托车会很累 但是骑汽车的特别来讲的话
We have to admit that cars have their advantages too.
咱们说汽车也有好的地方
For instance, if you're in Xinjiang,
比如你在新疆
or in Tibet,
你在西藏啊
if you really think about it,
你可以其实来讲的话
if you're crossing a remote area,
如果你穿越无人区啊
you would definitely be much safer in a car.
那你肯定就是汽车要安全得多
Right?
对不对
A motorcycle could break down.
摩托车也要坏了
To be honest
你本身来讲
you don't have a tent with you
你身上没有帐篷
and you lack the experience of motorcycle touring
没有这个摩旅的经验
so you might have a tough time
你可能会比较惨
but I wouldn't go to such places for a road trip either
但是我呢我也不会去那种地方搞什么自驾游
and I would definitely ride to safe areas
然后我肯定也就是骑车去安全的地方
at most, maybe around Jiangsu, Zhejiang, and Shanghai
最多就是嗯这个江浙沪啊
or a loop around Beijing, Tianjin, and Tangshan
京津塘这么着转一圈
so to speak
所以本身来讲的话
This effect has few limitations
这个效果限制的并不多
So I was talking about the motorcycle
所以我就说这个摩托车呢啊
Electric scooters are the joy of the less fortunate
电瓶车呢是穷人的快乐啊
Many people say to Teacher Rong
很多人说荣老师
You're just showing off
你就是装逼啊
You do this and that
你就怎么怎么样
Then there are two kinds of criticism I get
然后骂我的人不就两种风声音吗
One is that I'm showing off
一种就是说我装逼啊
And you have the money
这个你有钱
But then, I don't spend money.
但是呢就不消费啊
Pretending to be poor.
装穷
How else can I put it?
另一种怎么说呢
I mean, I'm poor.
就是我是穷人
I am poor by nature. And then, pretending to be rich. Anyway, I get criticized for both. So, I'll take the middle ground. I guess I'll just be middle-class. The middle class is done for. Isn't that right? So, it's not too bad. But I don't work, so what about the middle class?
我本身就穷 然后装富 反正两种骂我的声音都有 那我就取其中嘛 那我就是一个中产吧 中产阶级就完了 是不是 所以挺好 可是中产阶级呢我又不上班
What do you think? The poor are indeed poor.
你说呢穷人呢也的的确穷啊
They don't even renovate their houses.
房子都不装修
Isn't that true?
是不是
But the rich aren't that rich either, are they?
可是你说富呢也富不到哪去
Right?
对不对
So, a lot of the time,
所以很多的时候来讲的话
he says no matter what,
他就说无论怎么样
others will always find a way to criticize you,
别人都有办法骂你
but you must know the truth about their actions.
但是你一定要知道别人的真实行为
The reason they criticize you is because they envy you.
别人骂你的原因是因为别人啊嫉妒你啊
when someone looks at you,
有人看你
they feel quite surprised,
他就觉得很诧异
they feel quite envious.
他就觉得很嫉妒
That’s how it goes.
所以来讲
You can't completely follow someone else's thoughts.
你没有办法完完全全照着别人的想法来
But what they say is one thing,
但是别人嘴上说一套啊
and what they think in reality is another.
背地里现实中他想的是另外一套
Those who criticize you,
挑你毛病的人呢
are usually not criticizing you specifically,
通常也不是说挑的你的毛病
but rather, they just enjoy the act of finding faults with you.
而是只是因为能挑你毛病这一件事情让他开心
That's how it is on the internet.
所以这网络上就是这样
So anyone can say anything.
所以任何人会说任何话
And they won't reveal their true thoughts no matter what.
他无论如何也不会把他内心里的真实想法
Let me tell you
告诉你
the honest truth is, it's all about jealousy and envy
真实想法呢就是嫉妒羡慕嫉妒恨啊
there's no reason for it
没有任何理由
you need to understand
你要知道
most people in this world tend to harbor ill will towards you
这世界上大部分人对你都是保持一种恶意的啊
a constant ill will it might be because you're a woman or because you're experiencing hair loss or simply because you're wealthy Or because you don't have money people look down on you, right? Why does the old lady from Xicheng look down on me?
一种恒常的恶意啊 可能因为就是你是女的 可能因为你脱发啊 或者因为你有钱 或者因为你没钱 就是各种看不起你对吧 所西城大妈看不起我是因为什么呢
Because she thinks I'm pretending to be rich
就是因为她觉得我是假装有钱人啊
I come from a family that has been poor for three generations
我是一个穷穷三代
The reason someone looks down on me is because
有人看不起我的原因是因为呢啊
I pretend to win people's hearts
就是我假装啊这个刁买人心啊
I could easily get by without a luxury car
明明可以不用开9号
but I can afford a Porsche
可以开保时捷的人
We really have to go to number 9
非要去开9号
This is just putting on an act for us to see
这就是做作惺惺作态表演给我们看的
Sigh, so both of these mindsets are present
唉所以就是这两种心态都有
Actually, let's talk about this a bit more
其实咱们再说一下
Now, this t talk and refuge in the United States
现在这个美国的这个t talk和refuge
Now, about posting on Xiaohongshu
现在上小红书这件事啊
Originally, it's because of many things
本来也是因为很多事情来讲的话
It's not something unheard of
不是大家闻所未闻
It's something widely enjoyed
乐那个乐那个怎么说喜闻乐见的
Because every country uses its own media
因为各国都要用自己的媒体
to portray the other as being in a terrible state
把对方描写成一副不堪的样子
making the other country seem like a living hell
你看对方的国家就是人间地狱
while things are quite good here
在我们这儿挺好
But after the Chinese and American people face off
但是中美人民这么一对仗以后
they find that they can really appreciate each other's strengths
发现的就是啊都能很欣赏对方的优点
Right? So many times I often say I have always maintained a cautious and serious attitude When it comes to the United States of America especially for the ordinary people there's no need to harbor such deep hostility
对不对 所以很多的时候我就常说啊 我官职一直保持着一种啊警惕认真的态度 就是我们对美利坚合众国 特别是老百姓来讲 没有必要抱着那么深的敌意
In many cases
很多的时候来讲啊
the people of China and the United States are among the happier in the world
中美人民来讲话是世界上比较幸福的人民
because both countries are quite powerful
因为中美两个国家都比较强大
we should be moving towards more cooperation
应该是走向更多的合作
rather than competition and division
而不是竞争与分裂啊
This is also one of our country's major policies
这也是我们国家的大政方针之一
Actually, we are willing to cooperate.
其实我们是愿意合作的
We don’t want to engage in confrontation.
不愿意搞对抗
Many things are like this.
很多东西来讲都是这样
So I think if someone can move freely between China and the U.S.,
所以我觉得如果一个人能在中美之间来回的
it’s a truly blessed thing.
自由的转悠来讲是一个非常幸福的事啊
It really is a very fortunate thing.
是真的是非常幸福的事
The two most powerful countries in the world.
这世界上两个最强大的国家
This has always been my view.
这是我一贯的看法
There’s no need for confrontation.
没必要搞confrontation
There's no need to act as a reverie
没必要作为reverie
Wherever you are, there's always bickering
在哪儿去哪儿互相掐
While in China, think about the good things in China
就在中国的时候想想中国的好
When in America, think about the good things in America, and that's just fine
在美国时候就想美国的好就挺好的
Then, this artificial wall will certainly be built up
然后这个人工的墙呢一定会建立起来
Sooner or later
早晚来讲的话
User data between China and the U.S. will still remain invisible to each other
中美之间的用户数据还是会互相看不见
But it's like the Christmas truce during World War I
但就像一战的这种圣诞节停战一样
It's a brief peace
这是一个短暂的和平
Let everyone be able to enjoy Being able to enjoy this brief peace is good enough I think in this world There might not be true understanding and peace But remember this short period of time
让大家呢能够享受 能够这种享受这种短暂的这种和平就很好 然后我觉得人世间呢 可能没有真正的理解和和平 但是记住这个短暂的这个时间啊
All the events that happen in this human world
这个人类世界上所有发生的事情了
Don't have a
都没有一个
One could say
可以说是
Actually, they all follow a certain logic
其实都有一个固定的一个逻辑在里边啊
No matter what happens in this world
无论这世界上发生的事哪啊
There's nothing new under the sun
阳光底下没有什么事情是新鲜的
So often, what's separated will eventually come together
所以很多的时候就是你分久必合
And what's together will eventually split apart
合久必分
You see it every day in the media
你天天在媒体上啊
American media criticizing China
美国媒体骂中国
Chinese media criticizing America, it's just a bunch of
中国媒体骂美国就一帮啊
So-called redneck patriotic bloggers
所谓的那个红脖子爱国博主啊
It's just outrageous
就很天啊
It’s like they’re more anxious than the official side all day long
整天就恨不得比官方还急
Every day they’re issuing challenges through the internet
天天就隔着网就宣战了
This kind of behavior is really scary
就这种就挺可怕的啊
Actually, I used to have a big presence on Weibo too
其实我以前在微博时候也大过
It’s this kind of image
就是这种这么一种形象
Because on Weibo, everything is so clearly divided
因为在微博就是泾渭分明嘛
You have to form cliques
要拉山头
Then you have to create factions, that’s how it goes
然后拉阵营就是这样
So no matter what
所以呢无论怎么样的话
It's just a state of mutual insults
就是一种对骂这种状态
So it's quite boring
所以很无聊
You'll find that in life, people can actually foster cooperation
你会发现人生之间呢其实能从促成合作
And become friends more often
能做成朋友的人更多
So many people who really watch the content If they don't make judgments To be honest It's better to absorb the useful parts for yourself You can distance yourself from it Just one curse and they're gone Actually, it doesn't do you any good in life For me, it's a matter of indifference
所以很多人如果要是真是看过的内容啊 如果不做评价 其实来讲的话 吸收自己有用那部分的更好 你一击脱离 骂一句就走了 其实对你人生没有任何好处 对我来讲的话是无关痛痒的事
You're not my audience
你不是我的观众
You're not my follower
你不是我的粉丝
Whether you like me or not doesn't matter to me
你看喜不喜欢我对我来讲都不重要
Many people leave long comments
很多人评论一大堆
What they say can be quite insightful
说的话也是真知灼见
But if they don't follow, it doesn't matter
但是呢就是不关注不关注来讲的话
It doesn’t matter.
那也无所谓
So, coming to the point,
所以来讲的话
you mean you’re not my target audience, right?
你就说不是我的取悦对象对吧
I won’t cater to,
我就不会为
let alone change my views to match yours.
更不会为你的观点而改变我自己的观点啊
And in life,
而且人生在世
to be honest, there are so many channels,
说实在的这么多种频道
you can watch whatever you want.
你想看哪个都可以啊
Today we talked about the issue of motorcycle bans.
咱们今天说了说禁摩的问题
We also talked about the issue of ordinary people in China and the U.S. keeping accounts.
又说了说中美老百姓对账的问题啊
So, many things in this world,
所以人世间很多东西呢
involve breaking through a cognitive illusion,
都在一种破除一种认知迷局
and overcoming another limitation on this issue.
另一种局限上这个问题
What makes me happiest isn't how those who criticize me view me,
我最开心的不是这些骂我的人怎么看我
but what my followers think of me.
我最开心的是我的一些粉丝啊
Many of my followers and how they perceive me,
可以说很多粉丝他们怎么看我
that's what truly matters.
这才是最关键的
And it's not just about how they see me.
而且不是他们怎么看我
It was me who played a real role in their lives And that real role is to alleviate psychological stress Most of the time I break down the issues I dissect them thoroughly I talk at length about them
是我在他们的生命中起到了一个真实的作用 这个真实的作用就叫做啊缓解心理压力 很多的时候来讲 我把一些问题掰开了 揉碎了 在里边滔滔不绝的在那里边讲啊
In practice, this actually reduces people's anxiety levels
大家呢实际来讲就把这焦虑水平呢降低了
And I explain some of these issues
而且我把有些问题的这些啊
I delve into the specifics and clarify them
具体的问题呢给他讲透了
To put it bluntly, afterwards
讲的直白了以后呢
it actually dispels that feeling
反而就破除了这种感觉
why are you anxious
你为什么而焦虑
right
对不对
are you anxious about your house or your car
你为房子焦虑还是为车焦虑
or are you anxious about your partner
你还是为伴侣焦虑
or about the future
还是为未来焦虑啊
none of these are necessary
都没有必要啊
so in this regard
所以这个东西来讲
Since a 40-year-old has just gone through these pitfalls
由于一个40岁的人刚刚踩过这些坑啊
and is here to share these insights with you
然后给你去讲述这些东西来讲
it might truly be a fitting state
可能真的是比较合适的一个状态
so this is naturally where I should be
所以这就是我应该自然而然存在的一个状态
this is the place I should be in
所以这个就是我应该待的位置
this is also what I believe
所以这也是我觉得啊
is about playing my part effectively
所谓的啊发挥自己的这个实际的作用
whether I win the BILIBILI UP100 or not
拿不拿百大啊
whether I have 1 million or 2 million followers
粉丝过不过100万还是200万
Can I pick up Guangzi?
能不能接到广子
These things are not important.
这些东西都不重要
What's important is that I can serve my current audience.
重要的是我能够不服务
I am unique to my audience. So these things are knowledge. A key reason for me to move forward. Is that a large part of the people are strangers to you. Some of them are just spectators.
我现在的这些观众 我对我的观众而言是独一无二的 所以这些东西是知识 让我往下走的一个重要原因啊 就是重要一大部分人跟你是陌路啊
Some people are just spectators
有一部分人是看客
But there are people who truly appreciate you
但是有一部分人是真正欣赏你的
They are the ones who love you
是爱你的人啊
These are your core followers
这些东西是你的核心的铁粉啊
These people are the most important, like at my recent fan meet-up
这些人最关键就好像我这次粉丝见面会
I felt so great
我为什么感觉非常好
Because there were about 30 people
因为有那么30几个啊
Almost 40 people
快40人了啊
These children especially came from far away
这个这些小朋友们特地啊特地从远方来过来
Just to catch a glimpse of this old man
就为了看我这老头子一眼
In the course of life,
这个人生当中呢来讲
I tell you, doing tough things will always pay off.
我跟你说做这种事就是做难事必有所得
So, doing such things,
所以干了这种事
feels like it really makes a difference in people's lives.
就感觉上就是在大家的人生当中啊
It really had an impact.
真的起了作用了
People brought me gifts,
大家带了礼物给我
came to see me,
大家过来看我
spent money on me,
大家给我花钱
cheered for me.
大家给为我喝彩
These things, for me personally,
这些东西本身对于我一个个人来讲啊
are a tremendous encouragement.
其实是一个非常莫大的鼓励
Because I am actually divorced,
因为我本身其实就是一个离婚了啊
a man full of energy but with no place to channel it, an old man, but thankfully, people have stuck by me, listened to my ramblings, endured my endless talk, and even found my twisted logic useful.
有劲儿没地儿使的一个孤家寡人啊 一个老头子 但是呢承蒙大家不离不弃啊 把我的这些废话 把我的这些滔滔不绝的 这个乱七八糟的歪理邪说还能够啊听得进去
And that's what makes me feel accomplished,
还能够觉得有用
and in turn, I've helped others.
然后这个东西就是大家成就了我
It's a mutual relationship,
我也成就了大家
and that's the best feeling,
也是一个相互的关系
not about how many people like you.
就这种感觉最好
In life, many things can be said,
而不是在于你被多少人喜欢
you might not be the flashy motorcycle,
所以在人生当中很多东西来讲话
you are the motorcycle,
你未必你就是那辆摩托车
you might not be as shiny and sleek as a car,
你就是那辆摩托车
able to dominate the main roads,
你可能没有汽车那么的光鲜亮丽
or fetch a high price, right?
能占据主干道
You might just be a motorcycle,
能卖很多钱对吧
not even an expensive BMW motorcycle,
你可能就是辆摩托车
not the kind that can socialize with bikers,
你甚至不是很贵的BMW摩托车
you might just be a regular scooter,
你也不是那种啊
with a big frame,
能够出去跟机车圈里的机车员们能够交流的
right?
你可能就是一个普通的轻骑小踏板弯梁车啊
But you solve the need for urban commuting,
有一个二八大杠
you meet the most important needs of an ordinary person's life,
对不对
you might not be as flashy,
但是你解决了城市通勤的需要
but being practical is enough.
你解决了一个普通人生活的一个最重要的东西
In many aspects of our lives,
你可能没有那么光鲜亮丽
that's where the value lies, not in competing with handsome guys, not in competing with beautiful women, but in having your own place, having a position in the hearts of ordinary people, being able to help many people commute,
但是你实用这就可以了 我们人生中很多的时候 这价值就是这样 不在于你能跟帅哥一较高下 不在于你能跟美女啊pk一下 自在于你有自己的位置
that's your role.
你有普通人心目当中的地位
So, Brother Rong is that little motorcycle in your life.
你能够帮助很多人通勤啊
This is your role.
这个就是你的作用